<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2026 brie.gay -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>gay.brie.CheesePaper</id>
  
  <name>Cheese Paper</name>
  <summary>Organized writing in simple format</summary>
  
  <metadata_license>CC-BY-4.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>

  <developer id="gay.brie">
    <name>Brie</name>
  </developer>
  
  <description>
    <p>
      Cheese Paper is a text editor for writing long form prose, particularly fiction. Projects are broken down into scenes which each have notes and summaries, and can be moved around independently.
    </p>
    <p>
      Features:
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>See your notes as you write: jot down something for later, plan our where a scene will go before writing it, or summarize a scene to help organize your story</li>
      <li>Fill out notes in the editor: Dedicated documents for characters and information about the world</li>
      <li>Syncing support: delete files, move them, or add new ones. Cheese Paper will automatically process it, no restart required</li>
      <li>Simple files: the file format is specifically designed to be simple enough to edit on a phone. Sync to another device and access your project at all times</li>
      <li>Themes: Use supplied dark and light themes, or create your own</li>
      <li>Outline Export: Produce a single file outline containing your notes (but not story prose) which can easily be shared</li>
      <li>Story Export: Combine all of the scenes into a single markdown file that can easily be transformed into a wide variety of formats, including epub, docx, html, or pdf (with programs such as Pandoc)</li>
      <li>Randomize your theme: text too readable? Colors too pleasant? Not enough whimsy? Randomize every single color with no coordination, no consistency, and no concern for contrast (to the horror of everyone around you)</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      The underlying text is all Markdown, so the file format is simple. Metadata is added to the underlying format in a TOML header, also simple and easy to edit. Any files created outside the editor are automatically read in and processed like any other files, even if some or all of the metadata is missing. It is entirely possible to create, edit, move, and delete files from another text editor, even your phone. Cheese Paper also plays nicely with syncing programs - if you sync the files on disk, it will happily load them.
    </p>

  </description>
  
  <launchable type="desktop-id">gay.brie.CheesePaper.desktop</launchable>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://brie.gay/images/cheese-paper/scene.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://brie.gay/images/cheese-paper/amaryllis%20character.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://brie.gay/images/cheese-paper/rose%20workshop%20worldbuilding.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#ebdbb5</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#a50062</color>
  </branding>

  <url type="homepage">https://brie.gay/cheese-paper/</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://codeberg.org/ByteOfBrie/cheese-paper</url>
</component>